Gagandeep Singh

Phone: (647) 991-9411 Email: gagandeepsingh099@gmail.com

SUMMARY

- In-depth knowledge of web application development.
- 3+ years of experience in Desktop & Server support.
- Efficient use of CRM, Servers, technical documentation and presentation tools.

Technical Expertise

Programming Languages
Software
HTML, CSS, Java Script, jQuery, Bootstrap, C++, Database scripting, JSON.
CMS: WordPress, Jira, Salesforce, MS office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Skill expertise : Troubleshooting IT systems, Ecommerce development, Database management,
Web development (WordPress/HTML/CSS/JavaScript/Bootstrap)

WORK EXPERIENCE

BlackBerry Enterprise Support Analyst

Sutherland Global Services, Windsor, ON

April 2017-Present

High-level: Being a part of enterprise team provides technical and network related support to IT contacts from corporations and government institutions that have purchased an Enterprise support contract.

- Typically work with network administrators who need support for physical and cloud-based BlackBerry Enterprise Servers connecting to Microsoft Exchange, Domino and GroupWise email servers.
- Deal with the functionality of email administration/delivery and mobile device management.
- Helping with all kinds of issues from single device activation to multiple server failures.
- Extensive network administration and support knowledge.
- Active usage of Salesforce CRM, and proprietary tools for resolution.
- Participating on an inbound priority-based queue to answer telephone based inquiries.
- Escalating when necessary to the appropriate escalation teams.
- Support to BlackBerry (Enterprise Server 5.X/10.X/12., Windows Server 2008/2012 with knowledge of ActiveSync, Lotus Domino Server and/or Microsoft Exchange Server 07/10/13.

E-commerce Developer (Internship)

Oct 2016- Dec 2016

Scouts Canada, Windsor, ON

- Managed, developed, and deployed e-commerce webpage using WordPress themes, plugins, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Designed textual and graphical content including product illustrations for the website.
- Transitioned content from old website to a new ecommerce website.
- Managed full project individually.

Web developer Dec 2014 - Dec 2015

Idea Cellular Limited, Jallandhar, India

- Maintained and updated HTML/CSS templates on a regular basis and as required for content updates
- Assisted in planning and implementing dynamic and online electronic commerce applications.
- Conducted layout design and construction for a variety of webpages as assigned.
- Provided technical support to other web design team members as directed.
- Coordinated work assignments to achieve milestone deadlines.

Full Stack Developer Aug 2012 – Jul 2014

Netmax Technologies Pvt Ltd, India

 Addressing client queries for websites based on PHP, HTML, CSS etc. Working on CMS such as WordPress, and creating custom CMS. Working with applications on core Java and the extended use of embedded C in microprocessors for DIY projects.

- Integration of programming languages and embedded hardware and implementation of Internet of things.
- Developed prototype pages using HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery & amp; PHP ensuring best possible user experience and reusability of the code.
- Apart from this, used to make prototypes of various everyday electronic systems and sub systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering (Electrical and Computer)

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

University of Windsor, Windsor, ON

Portfolio: gagandiep.github.io